Why do you owe your Kemerovo?
Почему вы вашим Кемерова должны у вас
Moscow takes away your coal, takes away your money, and
Москва забирает уголь забирает деньги а
you get your coal, which you
вам ваш же уголь который вы на своей
dug up on your Kemerovo land at the cost of your
земле Кемеровской выкопали ценой своей
life and health. You still have to
жизни и здоровья Вы ещё должны у Москвы
buy this coal from Moscow for crazy money.
этот уголь купить за бешеные деньги как
How is it fair for crazy money? Really,
в чём справедливость за бешеные прямо
Hello. Hello.  where did
Здравствуйте откуда
Mist not understand where are you from Mister
Мист не понял вы откуда Мистер
gman I am from Russia I understood what city I am from
гман Я с России понял город какой я из
Latvia gave go and you
Латвии дал го а вы
understood I am from Kiselevsk from Russia
от понял я с киселёвска с России
Kiselevsk Kiselevsk This is
Киселёвск Киселёвск Это
where Oh wow a thousandth city you don't
где О нифига себе тысячник город не
know where I don't know to be honest
знаете где не знаю честно говоря
thousandth Kiselevskiy I don't know where
тысячник киселёвский я не знаю где
Kemerovo region Kuzbass stop a
Кемеровская область кузбас стоп а
Kemerovo region This is where
Кемеровская область Это где
Kuzbass is at all have you heard of such a thing there is Donbass
Кузбасс слышали про такой есть Донбасс
there is Kuzbass Donbass everyone has heard of A
есть Кузбасс Донбасс все слышали А
Kuzbass where is this at all
Кузбасс где это вообще
Kuznetsk coal
такое Кузнецкий угольный
basin This is between Krasnoyarsk and
бассейн Это между Красноярском и
Novosibirsk I know Krasnoyarsk Novosibirsk
Новосибирск Красноярс знаю Новосибирск
I know some Kiselevsk Kuzbass
знаю какой какой-то Киселёвск кузбас
Kemerovo some such  These are some
Кемерова какие-то такие Это какие-то
small towns, a small region or
маленькие города маленькая область или
something. Well  Well, 100,000 people Kiselevsky, yes,
что Ну ну 100.000 человек киселёвский да
it's some kind of small
это какой-то маленький
town Well, so small that it's
городок Ну такой маленький что
a thousand people Well, now it's not 100 Well, the outflow of
тысячник Ну сейчас уже не 100 Ну отток
population is big How far is it from
населения большой Сколько от него до
Moscow
Москвы
4,000, so that's peace for
4.000 так это мира для
Russia, well,
России ну
peace, yes So what Well, people live everywhere,
мира да Ну и что Ну люди же везде живут
especially a lot  people
тем более много людей
live Novokuznetsk heard
живёт Новокузнецк слышали
no Novokuznetsk 500,000 half a million
нет Новокузнецк 500.000 полмиллиона
I I For the first time I hear from Latvia such cities
я я Впервые слышу из Латвии такие города
Kemer and Kemer - this is tu tu I know but you don't
Кемер а Кемер - это ту ту знаю а ты не
know where what cities in Latvia do you know
знаешь где какие ты Латвии города знаешь
Name Well in Latvia I don't know cities I
Назови Ну в Латвии Я городов не знаю я
just know that
просто знаю что
[laughter]
[смех]
la  I don't know there are many cities of course well
ла Не знаю городов там много конечно ну
there How many
там Сколько живёт
people live well in Latvia for example in an average
человек ну в латви например в среднем
city 10,000 to 20,000 no no don't
городе по 10.000 по 20.000 нене не
look in Latvia we have 50 million
смотри у нас в Латвии вообще 50 млн
people in general so in Riga there live 6 million
населения так в Риге живёт э 6 млн
people in
населения в
Dao Yes there are 6 million people in [ __ ]  in plc
дау Да там 6 млн населения в Даго в plc
5 e million population there are and there are even
5 э миллионов населения есть и там ещё
further nsl 3  million port city we have
дальше нсл 3 млн портовый город у нас
big cities you have some damn
большие города у вас какой-то блин
100,000 Well I don't know this is for us by
100.000 Ну это не знаю это у нас по
our standards 100,000 this is some kind of
нашим меркам 100.000 это какой-то там
town I don't know somewhere on the border
городишко я не знаю где-то на границе
Maybe there is a small one Well I understand Okay think
Может там маленький Ну понял Ладно думай
as you want in short when  I was at school
как хочешь короче когда я в школе учился
I want to tell you a story It's
хочу тебе одну историю Рассказать она
not a
не
quick one In short, a boy came to us from Latvia,
быстренько короче к нам из Латвии пацан
his name was Denis His father
приехал Денис звали его у него Отец там
worked there as someone Well, in short, he studied with us for a year
кем-то работал ну короче он у нас год
His father had to work at a
проучился отцу надо было по работе на
factory somewhere
заводе где-то у поработал
He worked  from Latvia he was from Riga there was this guy
он с Латвии он с Риги был вот этот пацан
Denis his name was Pushkin last name
Денис его звали Пушкин фамилия
Pushkin in short he studied for a year
Пушкин короче он этот год проучился
everyone borrowed money from everyone there were
всех у всех денег по занимал там типа
stickers like there were just like from the stolons there were
наклейки как раз были вот со столоны там
all sorts of
всякие
Schwarzenegger on Mike who
Шварцнегер на Майку который
promised everyone transfers he took three rubles from everyone
переводки всем наобещал у всех по трёшку
and  he knew that he
забрал и он знал что он и никому ничего
didn't
не
give anything to anyone, imagine how we treated Latvia later,
отдал прикинь как мы потом к латви сам
look, Latvians don't have a
относились так это смотри у латышей Нет
name  Denis is a Russian from Latvia was a
имени Денис это русский из Латвии был
Russian Russian on mahat' this is in short
русский русского на махать это короче
just like
прям как
good so it is with him Well okay I won't
годно так у него Ну ладно я тебе не буду
tell you Look this yes these are children of Russian
говорить Смотри это да это дети русских
soldiers we had them too I have him a
военных у нас были тоже у меня он
classmate too Sanya Prokhorov was with
одноклассник тоже Саня Прохоров был у
us no one  there is no name Sanya Yes in
нас же ни у кого нету имени Саня Да в
Latvia it is Sanya Denis it is all these
Латвии это Саня Денис это всё вот эти
Russians who came here they then
русские которые понаехали они потом их
kicked them out a little from here they went There they
немножко отсюда выгоняли они ездили Там
cheated Russians from other
на бабки разводили русских из других
schools so here is Sanya Prokhorov My
школ так вот Саня Прохоров Мой
classmate was also we sat in
одноклассник тоже был мы сидели в
Daugavpils at a desk for 11 years From the bell  before the
Даугавпилс за партой 11 лет От звонка до
bell they copied from each other Tic Tac
звонка списывали друг у друга Крестики
Toe they played sea battle and what do you know
нолики играли в морской бой и что знаешь
what now with Sanya Prokhorov
что теперь с Саней прохоровым
what he said Latvia when it joined
что он сказал Латвия когда вступила в
NATO he says I don't need your Latvia
НАТО он говорит Не нужно мне ваша Латвия
NATO I'll go to Great Russia he went
НАТО я поеду в Великую Россию поехал
went to
поехал в
Moscow and and what in  in the twenty-second
Москву и и что вот в двадцать втором
year he was mobilized and by Kherson
году мобилизовали его и под херсоном
you mean a drone flew in and
понимаешь ему Дрон прилетел и
everything was stupid in short there is a video of how  he runs
всё тупо короче видео есть как он бежит
his mother showed him his mother lives in Latvia and
мамка его показывала мамка в Латвии
still shows We
живёт ещё до сих пор показывала Мы
were collecting here in Latvia for Ukrainian
собирали тут в Латвии на украинские
drones and Sanya Prokhorov Took Polesie in short to
дроны а Саня Прохоров Взял полес короче
fight and our Latvian Drone with the
воевать и ему наш латвийский Дрон с
flag of Latvia flew to him like that
флагом Латвии так прилетел
[music]
[музыка]
right
прям ты по нём
now you just like a friend  You are sad
сейчас просто как подругу Ты тоскуешь
that no I am not sad, well, you are not sad, well, it's a
что нет не тоскую ну не тоскуешь ну
pity, damn No, it's not a pity at all, but it's not a pity that you spent
жалко а не жалко что ты с ним провёл
half your life with him there, well, it's not half your life that's a pity. It's a
полжизни там ну не полжизни жалко Вот
pity that I sat with him for 11 years and didn't give
Жалко что 11 лет я с ним сидел и не дал
him for that, damn, if I  I knew that he would go
ему за то что блин если бы я знал что он
to Ukraine to fight, damn it, yes
попрёт блин в Украину воевать да Я б ему
I would have given him Toda, our whole class would have given it to him
ещё Тода мы бы ему всем классом Дали бы
at graduation, you know, really, it's
на выпускном понимаешь реально от так
just that we had one, yes, money. In short,
просто у нас был один да дене Короче
maybe it was the one who
может это кстати тот который у тебя
borrowed money from you, he was also there for that  at
бабки занимал он тоже там на это на
graduation he took it and said glory to Russia in the
выпускном взял и сказал слава России в
tram station and then celebrated really
трам пункте дальше праздновал реально до
still
сих пор без зубов
walks around without teeth  stupid bald man bald Now
ходит ему тупо лысый мужик лысый Теперь
all
всю
life roots at graduation still
жизнь корнями на выпускном ещё
math teacher
учительница математики
achieved at
добивалась на
graduation Yes I will not say what
выпускном Да я не буду говорить что
the physicist did with him
физик с ним
Well no need Okay don't say I
делал Ну не надо Ладно не говори я
understood that's why that Sanya Prokhorov was It seems
понял поэтому та Саня Прохоров был Вроде
so normal and then he keeps saying he left
так нормально а потом всё говорит уехал
for Russia Great  Russia and everything died
в россиюшка Великая Россия и всё помер
and what is great and Russia is not great and how is
а что великая а Россия не великая а чем
it
она
Great Tsar here Look yourself
Великая царь вот Сам смотри
Tsar Ivan the Terrible Peter I Catherine
царь Иван Грозный Пётр I Екатерина
Stalin so And how is Russia great
Сталин так А чем Россия великая Вот
Look here Latvia is our Great we live God's
смотри Латвия наша Великая мы живём Бога
hall Prince Gaul and Prince Lagili the great
зала князь галий и князь лагали великие
princes who baptized Latvia  I
князья которые крестили Латвию кое
only know yours there is a guy from
только лагаю вашу знаю там чувак из
Lagali blogger there is such a guy I
лагали блогер там такой чувачок есть я
see here we have a prince Lagali
его смотрю вот у нас есть князь лагали
prince Semigallians they founded Moscow were
князь земгале они основали Москву были
still there and then the Tatar-Mongols
ещё пока а потом татаро-монголы
captured it they still haven't
захватили её его до сих пор не
given him back for this I am still the first time  I hear
отдают за это я ещ первый раз слышу
now I need to e Well, when I
сейчас надо я е Ну как
look I also love history Well, this is the
посмотрю я тоже историю люблю Ну это
first time I've heard Yes, look, why is that
первый раз я вот слышал Да смотри почему
why Moscow is called
вот почему Москва называется
Moscow Why Yes, in Latvian, in
Москва Почему Да это по-латышски в
translation, Moscow, it's called the big
переводе Москва это называется большое
swamp translation The thing is that the prince of
болото перевод Дело в том что князь
Latgale, the prince of Semigallian when  conquered
латгалии князь земгале когда завоевали
this territory, recaptured it from the Finno-Ugric peoples, yes,
эту территорию отбили у фино угров да э
they decided to found a settlement there and
они решили основать там поселение и
called it Moscow, the Big Swamp, that's
назвали его Москва большое болото это по
Latvian, yes, and there was the first fortress, it
латышский да И там был первая крепость
was Latvian, there was a Catholic church there,
была латышская вот там была церковь
and then when the
католическая А потом когда
Tatar-Mongols,
татаро-монголы
uh, attacked Europe, yes, they captured
ээ нападали на Европу да Они захватили
it,  this
вот эту
territory of the Volga-Oka Interfluve
территорию Волго окского Междуречья
was captured Moscow was recaptured from the prince then the
захватили Москву отбили у князя тогда
prince of Semigallian was wounded and he well he
князь земгале был ранен и его ну его
was able to be evacuated and so the troops of Latvia
смогли эвакуировать так и войска Латвии
retreated under the onslaught of Genghis Khan Since
отступили под натиском Чингисхана С тех
then Moscow fell under the protectorate of the
пор Москва попала под протекторат
Golden Horde Tatars Mongols Yes Prince
Золотой Орды татара монголов Да Князь
Ivan the Terrible it was he was it  how is
Иван Грозный это же был он был этим как
it Genghis Khan he
оно чингизидов он монголом
was a Mongol damn  What the hell did you tell me?
был блин Нифига ты мне что сказал Да его
Well, look at this. In books they call him
Ну смотри это Это его в книжках называют
Ivan the Terrible. And so he had
Иван Грозный А так он носил
the title of Chingizid Akhmed
титул чингизид Ахмед
Pasha. Why is he
Паша Он же по почему он
Pasha? Its
Паша это
like a Chingizid Akhmed Pasha.
вообще как чинт чингизид Ахмет Паша
Because look at Chingizid because
потому что посмотри чингизид потому что
its just, ah, its just  I explain because
это вообще ах это вообще уже Объясняю по
this is a Mongolian Tatar
это ж татара монгольская
from Why Genghis Khan Because he was
от Почему чингизид Потому что он был
a subject of Genghis Khan, that's why he was called
подданным Чингисхана поэтому и назывался
Genghis Khan Dasha and I explain why
чингизид Даша причём ту объясняю Почему
Akhmed because he was born with the name
Ахмед потому что он от рождения имя
Akhmed, he was a Muslim, a thunderstorm And why
Ахмед он мусульманином был гроз А почему
Pasha because among the Turks Yes, among the Turkic
Паша потому что у тюрков Да у тюркских
peoples, that's the military leader  he was called
народов так военно начальник назывался
here he is from the Tatar
вот он из татарского
family by Why
рода по Почему почему он на каза нал
why did he attack Kazan Kazan
Почему он на Казань напал Казань Казань
there are only Tatars living there so he
там татары одни живут так вот он тоже
was also a Tatar he attacked Kazan
был татарином он напал на Казань потому
because he fought with his brother
что он с братом своим
and where were the Russians at that time
воевал а русские где были в это время
these are Russians  there was no look queen
это русских не было смотри царица
Catherine was German true Peter  I was
Катерина была немкой правда Пётр I был
when the Germans Yes seized the throne drove the
когда немцы Да захватили престол выгнали
Tatar-Mongols from the throne Chingizids and
татаро-монгол из престола чингизидов и
these Akhmeti Yes
ахмети этих Да вот
then sat who the Germans are these are the
тогда восседали кто немцы это ВС
German tsars were until Lenin Yes
немецкие цари были пока Ленин Да не
overthrew the German
скинул немецких
tsars and then who Look you were ruled by
царей и потом кто Смотри вами правили
Chingizids Tatars then Germans then a Jew
чингизиды татары потом немцы потом еврей
Lenin then a Georgian  Stalin and then
Ленин потом грузин Сталин а потом
some Ukrainians and again everything is there with
какие-то там украинцы и снова там всё у
you Russian rulers name at least one
вас русских правителей назви хоть одного
Russian
русского
ruler Well and now who is this again erpo
правителя Ну а сейчас кто опять ере
not true Yes I have known for a long time that
по не правда Да это я уже давно знаю что
Medvedev is also Medvedev he is Mendelssohn
Медведев тоже Медведев он же Мендельсон
on his mother's side yes Medvedev I don't know  who but he I
по маме да Медведев я не знаю кто но он
don't know I don't know who I can't Putin's
не знаю не знаю кто не могу У Путина
mother's last name you
мамы какая фамилия
know no
знаете нет
Goldman Well, that's Jewish Well that's all
гольдман Ну вот еврейская Ну вот и всё
he grew up in the St. Petersburg synagogue he's the same
он в Питерской синагоге вырос он же е
here in his youth Yes there are more photos of
вот в в молодости Да есть ещё фотографии
him with this
как он с этой
kippah He's the son of Ravina the son  Rabbi of this St.
кипо Он сын Равина сын Равина этой
Petersburg
Питерской
synagogue That is, you
синагоги То есть у вас русского
did not have a Russian ruler, you had at least one Russian
правителя не было хоть одного русского
ruler  Latvians then there were
правителя у вас были латыши потом были
Mongols, Tatars, then these
монголы татары потом эти
uh Germans, then Jews, then Georgians,
ээ немцы да потом евреи потом грузин
then Ukrainians, then Jews again, in short,
потом украинцы потом снова евреи короче
who doesn't rule you, you have a Russian
кто вами только не правит у вас русского
ruler?
правителя
No, listen, and they all rake in the towel, and we
Нет слушай и все под себя гребут а мы
live like this, and Well, how can I put it rudely, in
живём так и Ну как грубо сказать в
bast shoes, and we lived like this  in bast shoes and we live in
лаптях так и жили в лаптях так и живём в
bast shoes Yes why Because look you have an
лаптях Да почему Потому что смотри у вас
occupation power sitting in the Kremlin
в Кремле сидит оккупационная власть Она
Why is it robbing Russians
почему она в вас грабит русских потому
because you are a foreign people to it
что вы для неё чужой
because
народ потому что вот
they give gas to Europe and we have so many cities and
они Европу газ а у нас городов столько а
here is absolutely your Kemerovo
га вот абсолютно вашей Кемеровской
regions probably gas oh
области наверное газа о
true No of course coal we live on coal
правда Нет конечно у угля мы на угле
from us all from us all of Russia from
живём от нас вся от нас вся России от
us for export trains straight coal And
нас на экспорт эшелоны прямо угля А
why I I read that your Kirov
почему я вот я читал что ваше Кировской
region Who lives in the private sector are
обла Кто в частном секторе живёт
forced to buy for Sky-high prices
вынуждены покупать за Заоблачные цены
Yes although we live  The media is here and we buy I
Да хотя живём СМИ тут а покупаем Я вот
also read that Yes, I remembered about your
тоже читал что Да я вспомнил про вашу
Temirovskaya region, I read that they
Темиров скую область вот я читал что там
even stopped paying wages to miners
шахтёрам зарплату уже даже перестали
at some mines  there is
выплачивать на некоторых Шахтах есть
such a thing well it was Well now they are apparently
такое ну это было Ну сейчас они видать
throwing dust in their eyes or something Well they raised the salary
пыль глаза пускают или что Ну Зарплату
Well in short it
Ну короче она до европейская вообще
doesn't reach the European level at all Well in general I see Yes
никак не доходит Да вообще я смотрю Да у
here in Latvia like the mines get 10
нас в Латвии типа вот шахт получает в 10
times more than the sha in Kemerovo and the question
раз больше чем ша в Кемерово и вопрос
arises  why do you owe your Kemerovo
получается почему вы вашим Кемерово
Moscow takes away your coal
должны у вас Москва забирает уголь
takes away your money and you get your coal
забирает деньги а вам ваш же уголь
which you dug up on your Kemerovo land at
который вы на своей земле Кемеровской
the cost of your life and health You
выкопали ценой своей жизни и здоровья Вы
still have to buy this coal from Moscow for
ещё должны у Москвы этот уголь купить за
crazy money how is it fair
бешеные деньги как в чём справедливость
for Crazy really
за Бешенные прямо
what  I do
реально в чём
n't know Well, there is no justice, no, that's how it
не знаю Ну нет справедливости нет так
turns out. Look, earlier, yes. Earlier,
получается смотри раньше да Раньше от
Genghis Khan took money from you. No, first
вас деньги забирал Чингисхан Нет сначала
Latgale and Semigallians, our Latvian princes,
латгалии и земгале наши князья латышские
and then Genghis Khan, then the German kings. And
да потом Чингисхан потом немецкие цари И
so on. When will you, Kemerovo, gain
так дальше когда вы Кемеров обретёте
independence so that your coal can work for
независимость чтобы ваш уголь работал на
you? You can be millionaires.  like in
вас вы ж можете быть миллионерами как на
Donbass Well, Putin
Донбассе Ну Донбасс тоже же вон Путин
took over Donbass too yes yes they wanted they wanted in
прибрал да да они хотели они хотели для
order to get their own
того чтобы короче получило они своим
they fed on coal and Putin, why did he say that?
кормились а Путин для чего он сказал он
No, he didn't want Donbass to be
Нет он не захотел чтобы Донбасс был
independent. You see, he wants to milk it
независим Понимаешь он хочет доить
because Putin is not
потому что Путин Он же не
Russian. They all take all the money for themselves in the Kremlin. The
русский они Все забирают себе в Кремль
thing is, I don't
все бабки так дело в том что вот я не
understand how much they need.  mto once
понимаю сколько им надо-то мто один раз
Yes the point is this
Да суть такая это
is the logic of a conqueror he comes to a
ж логика завоевателя он приходит на
territory and must suck everything out of it
территорию и должен высосать из неё всё
because he does not know whether he will hold the
потому что не знает удержит Он завтра
territory tomorrow or not he treats
или не удержит территорию он относится к
you Putin as conquered people you understand
вам Путин как завоёвано народу понимаешь
you are just dumb for him you are
вы для него просто челя вы для него
just servants for him  who do it for him This is what
просто слуги которые для него делают Вот
they mine this coal Yes, I know
это добывают этот уголь Да вот знаю
this, I know when
такое знаю когда вот приезжает
some
какой-нибудь
Great One, Velmo, comes Well,
Великий там Вельмо
not even Putin's But
Ну там даже не путинский А вот
some
какой-нибудь
Governor's and there everything Oh, all the paths need to be
Губернаторский и там все Ой надо всё
swept and painted so that he can pass there,
подмести покрасить чтобы он прошёл там
well, that's it  just so that everything would be like this you know it
ну вот прям чтоб было всё как вот знаешь
pisses me off I don't give a damn about all this
меня аж бесит плевать охота на это всё
like they have like kings That's how it used to be like
типа что у них как цари Вот раньше были
this but
самое да
it turns out this governor gets
получается этот губернатор получает
money for your coal  for yours Yes he himself
деньги за ваш уголь за ваш Да сам ничего
does nothing yes And you still don't dance in front of him
не делает да А вы ещё перед ним не он
here in Latvia and in general in
пляшет вот у нас в Латвии и вообще в
Europe as a president governor deputy
Европе как президент губернатор депутат
he is a servant of the
он слуга
people he comes he reports
людей он приходит он отчитывается никто
no one runs there kisses him but in Russia he
не бегает там его не целует а в России
really comes like a tsar  not even
реально как царь приезжает даже не то
Putin but some minor official
что Путин а какой-то мелкий чиновник
comes to
приезжает
him carpet bread salt girls to the bathhouse In short, everyone
ему ковёр хлебсоль девчонок в баню Все
lines up let's congratulate our
выстраиваются поздравим нашего
representative deputy of the defense department of the
представителя заместителя отдела обороны
governor and
губернатора и
all this is so annoying such crap and
всё вот это вот бесит такая фигня а как
how do you protest against this after that
как вы после против этого протестует
Why do you allow yourself to be humiliated like that
Почему вы позволяете себя так
to this question Generally difficult
унижать на этот вопрос Вообще трудный
answer I don't even know what to say I'm
ответ Я даже не знаю что говорить-то я
saying that I'm against it well
говорю что я против этого ну
damn We have many who were against them
блин Вон у нас многие кто был против их
now they are gone And where did
сейчас нету А где
they disappear really like the gulags there
они ну сгинули ну реально как гулаги там
used to
раньше ла
be because it's called occupation
был потому что это оккупация называется
Freedom is not so easy
Свобода так просто не
Given it is
Дан это
at If we look Yes there is metallurgy
у Если мы смотрим Да там за металлургия
there coal metallurgy here When the war
тамде уголь металлургия тут Когда война
was forty-first forty-fifth half of
была сорок первый сорок пятый половина
iron well here for Tanks for everything for
железа ну вот для Танков для всего для
guns for all sorts of things, all of them came from Kuzbass,
орудий для всяких там вся из Кузбасса
50% of them. They didn't do anything here, the finished
50% Тут ничего не делали тут готовое
iron was sent to the Ural factories. And they were
железо пускали уже на Уральские заводы А
already making tanks there, well, I
там уже делали танки там ну что они там
don't know what they were doing there, but all the iron
делали не знаю но железо отсюда всё
was taken from here, so look, it turns out that's the
бралось так вот смотри получается да э
only way to  prosperity of Kuzbass
единственный путь к процветания Кузбасса
is independence yes Kuzbass must
это независимость да кузбас должен
mature and declare that it is Enough to feed
созреть и заявить что он Хватит кормить
Moscow here Remember and I understand that
Москву вот Запомни и я понимаю что не
this hour has not come yet but you
пришёл ещё это этот час но вы
Kemerovo Yes Novokuznetsk residents should all
Кемеров Да новокузнечане все должны
carry in your souls Yes this fire of
носить у себя в душе Да вот этот огонь
Freedom You
Свободы Вы
should whisper to each other
должны шёпотом передавать друг другу
you know how our ancestors passed on
знаешь как наши предки передавали во
during the Great Patriotic War I know I
время Великой Отечественной войны знаю
know yes that it's enough to feed Moscow it's enough
знаю да что хватит кормить Москву хватит
to feed Moscow it's enough to feed Moscow This
кормить Москву хватит кормить Москву Это
should sit in the heart simply in the heart of
должно сидеть в сердце просто в сердце у
every Kemerovo resident and When the hour comes and
каждого кемеровчанин и Когда будет час и
because you know how the Soviet Union
потому что ты знаешь как Советский Союз
was a prison of nations Yes  like the Russian
была тюрьма народов Да как и Российская
empire and then gopp and collapsed right at
империя а потом гопп и развалилась вот в
this moment at this moment  everyone as one
этот момент в этот момент все как один
must come out as one Chechens for
должны выйти все как один чеченцы за
independence Tatars for independence
независимость татары за независимость
Bashkortostan Yakuts and Kemerovo Kuzbass this is
башкорт якуты и Кемеров кузбас это
really the richest region it should
реально богатейший регион он должен
become should become just a fairway of the
стать должен стать просто фарватера
struggle for independence in
борьбы за независимость в
Siberia Well, you are great Avangard yes
Сибири Ну ты молодец Авангард да
I really believe you I believe because
реально я верю вас Я верю потому что
you know Russians  people Russian people They will
знаешь русские люди русские люди Они
never allow themselves to be ruled
никогда не позволят чтобы ими правила
Here is some kind of clique that
Вот какая-то такая клика которая просто
will simply rob them was a Russian person
их будет грабить был ру русский человек
No, it's because you have forgotten your
Нет это потому что вы забыли своё
Russian nature And how many were Minin and
русское ество А сколько были Минин и
Pozharsky
Пожарский
Remember, they simply gathered The people gathered
Вспомни собрались просто Народ собрался
and drove out the adversaries
и прогнал супостатов
and Remember  Stepan
а Вспомни Степана
Razin What Uprisings he did and Ermak set
Разина Какие Восстания он делал а Ермака
all of Siberia on fire And so
всю Сибирь зажёг всю И вот так
when the tsar in Moscow or the tsarina thinks
когда царь в Москве или царица думает
that everything is already in his
что всё у него уже в
hands the people's Anger like a match lights
руках народный Гнев как спичка зажигает
one person the second the third and
одного человека второго третьего и
the flash goes like a spill of fuel oil on the Black
вспышка идёт как разлив мазута на Чёрном
Sea you understand That's all  and it's
море понимаешь Так всё и оно
everywhere Therefore yes
всюду Поэтому да
Remember that you are
Вспомни что ты
Russian
русский
sit and tell others  and get ready get
сиди другим рассказывай и готовьтесь
ready and do something because
готовьтесь и что-то делайте потому что
Stop
Хватит
sitting don't think
сидеть не думай
do do it already
делай делайте уже
finally because as
наконец-то потому что как говорил Бог
our God Jesus Christ said life is not eternal but
наш Иисус Христос жизнь не вечно а
fleeting the enemy won't let you in won't let you in It's
скоротечно вра не пускают не пускают Там
closed there stands this Apostle Paul or
закрыто там стоит Апостол этот Павел или
Peter and says A  what were you doing when
Пётр и говорит А ты что делал когда
the Kremlin
Кремлёвский тебя
robbed you And I was saying
ограбили А я был говорит
everything and only the one who fought was
всё и только тот кто боролся тому
promised the Kingdom of Heaven as
обещано Царство небесное как писалось
the Gospel of the Andronicus was written
Евангелие от андроников
Look at yours you lived How old are
Посмотри на свою ты прожил Сколько лет
you How old are you 46 46 Look at me
тебе Сколько тебе лет 46 46 Смотри мне
43 I'm in Latvia How beautiful I look at 43
43 Я в Латвии Как красиво выгляжу в 43
How did Russia bring you to this? It sucked
Как тебя россия-то довела она выпила из
all the juices out of you. How much is your salary?
тебя все соки Сколько у тебя зарплата
Now the salary is 50,000,
Сейчас зарплата 50.000
not even that. It's a disgrace. Our homeless child
даже нету это позор у нас беспризорный
gets 700 euros just for being
получает 700 евро просто за то что он
homeless, and you work for 500 euros.
беспризорный а вы работаете за 500 евро
This is impossible. How can you allow yourself to be treated like this?
Это невозможно как это как вы с собой
So what is the essence of your life? Do you work
Так в чём суть твоей жизни ты работаешь
in the morning?  you get up you go to work you
с утра встаёшь идёшь на работу
come back you have nothing in this
возвращаешься нету у тебя ничего в этой
life you come to this little I
жизни ты приходишь в эту маленькую я
see a little room
вижу маленькую комнатушке
your life do at least something do so
твоя жизнь сделай хоть что-то сделай так
you can go down in history you can set the
ты можешь войти в историю ты можешь
whole Kemerovo region on fire you can
зажечь всю кемеровскую область ты можешь
become
стать
the one who will do something  there are no
тем кто что-то сделает не бывает
small people there are small
маленьких людей бывают маленькие
actions I believe in you you can do it come on
поступки я в тебя верю ты можешь давай
squeak
писка
dig up find Telegram right now axis
копись най Telegram прям зараз ось
AK this is very and very important YouTube is busy
АК це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
with us through srg or in your ban and very
нас через срг ор в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show people sometimes I don't
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams to that  in order for
показуе информация про стримы тому для
us to write an operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
right now and while there is
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в окм
interesting and useful information in the video
вдео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we will oblige you to keep a constant
и ми повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
independently in order to show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write A
пиши A